Guide to the Donald MacInnis Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Research files, 1899-2002; Series I
  - Filed by topic
    - Min Consul - American Consulate
      - American Consultate reports on political and economical conditions in Foochow district, 1915-1927 (Box 16, Folder 167-168)
      - Historical sketch of political conditions in Fukien 1911-1923, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 169)
      - DM notes, maps statistics (Box 17, Folder 170)
    - Min River Boat Songs (Box 17, Folder 171)
      Music by Malcolm F. Farley, Mu Lan Ts'v, and "Chinese Songs-Eunice Smith"
    - Missionary illness, death, resignation (Box 17, Folder 172)
    - Missionary problems (Box 17, Folder 173)
      Typed list of 17 Missionary problems
    - Missionary rosters (Box 17, Folder 174)
    - Mothers and children (Box 17, Folder 175)
    - Motives for mission, critique of mission (Box 17, Folder 176)
    - Opium (Box 18, Folder 177)
    - Paper making (Shaowu) (Box 18, Folder 178)
    - Persecution cases; legal cases (Box 18, Folder 179)
    - Photographs, incl. of Foochow mission (ca. 1900); Methodist church pastors of Kutien (ca. 1900); missionaries and missionary families (ca. 1930s); Chinese familties; boat travel, etc. (Box 18, Folder 179a)
    - Pirates (Box 18, Folder 180)
    - Report of Anglo Chinese College War Days at Yangkow (Box 18, Folder 181)
    - Reports from Foochow (Box 18, Folder 182)
    - Revolution, 1927 (Box 18, Folder 183)
    - Revolution in Shaowu, 1911 (Box 18, Folder 184)
    - River travel, coastal steamer, travel by foot (Box 19, Folder 185)
    - Separations (Box 19, Folder 186)
    - Schools (Box 19, Folder 187)
    - Shanghai Directory (Box 19, Folder 188)
    - Shaowu district (Box 19, Folder 189)
    - Steam navigation in China (Box 19, Folder 190)
    - Tai-Ping Rebellion (Box 19, Folder 191)
    - "Teaching Children in China at the Canton Christian College" (pamphlet), 1915 (Box 19, Folder 192)
    - Treaties (Box 19, Folder 193)
    - U.S. "protection" U.S. consul, navy (Box 19, Folder 194)
    - Vegetarians (Box 19, Folder 195)
    - Village evangelism (Box 20, Folder 196)
    - Warlords (Box 20, Folder 197)
    - War with Japan, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 198)
    - Women's work (Box 20, Folder 199)
    - Youth and Faith, Liaowang "Christianity fever" (Box 20, Folder 220)
  - Notes and sources
    - ABCFM archives; Boston and Harvard (Box 21, Folder 221)
    - Bibliographical references (Box 21, Folder 222)
    - Biographical style- format (Box 21, Folder 223)
    - Bowdoin College library (Box 21, Folder 224)
    - Chapter contents (Box 21, Folder 225)
    - Church Missionary Society archives, London (Box 21, Folder 226)
    - Harvard archives (Box 21, Folder 227)
    - Hoover Institution archives (Box 21, Folder 228)
    - Ideas, outline (Box 21, Folder 229)
    - Index terms, chronology (Box 21, Folder 230)
    - Methodist archives, Drew University (Box 21, Folder 231)
    - Min River Valley Project- Notes and Outline (Box 22, Folder 232)
    - Missionary families mentioned in the book - correspondence, index, permissions (Box 22, Folder 233-234)
    - Oregon State University archives (Box 22, Folder 235)
    - Oregon, University of - archives (Box 22, Folder 236)
    - Seventh Day Adventist archives (Box 22, Folder 237)
    - Yale Divinity School Library archives (Box 22, Folder 238-239)
- Writings, 1945-1995; Series II
  - Writings of MacInnis
    - Religious Policy and Practice in Communist China (The MacMillan Company, NY), 1972 (Box 23, Folder 240)
    - "A New Humanity in People's China" - in The Holy Cross Quarterly; "How China Feeds 800 Million" - in China Notes, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 241)
    - "Gods are all right for the rich: the poor have the Eighth Route Army" - in One World; "The Present Reality of China and the Christian Relationship to It" - paper for China Conference held at Maryknoll, 1976,1979 (Box 23, Folder 242)
    - "Religious Revival in China" in The Christian Century, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 243)
    - "Secularism and Religion in China: The Problem of Transcendence" - chapter in Contemporary Chinese Philosophy;; issue of Mission Forum edited by DM, 1982, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 244)
    - Religion in China Today: Policy and Practice (Orbis Books, NY) and German translation, 1989, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 245)
    - "The Little Flock and the Chinese Protestant Church" - paper delivered at Eastern Fellowship, American Society of Missiology, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 246)
    - Book review in Missiology, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 247)
    - "The Little Flock (Assembly Christians) and the Protestant Church in China" - paper deliverd at "Religion in Contemporary China" conference, Washington DC, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 248)
    - "Report of a ten-day visit to the upriver churchers of northwest Fujian, November, 1998" (Box 25, Folder 248)
  - Writings of others
    - Barrett, William E., 1967 (Box 25, Folder 249)
      The Red Lacquered Gate
    - Burr, Leona L., 1965 (Box 25, Folder 250)
      Dear Ones at Home
    - Epsey, John J., 1945 (Box 26, Folder 251-252)
      Minor Heresies
    - Fung, Raymond, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 253)
      Households of God on China's Soil
    - Gwynn, R.M., et. al., 1986 (Box 26, Folder 254)
      T.C.D. in China: A History of the Dublin University Fukien Mission 1885-1935
    - Lacy, Walter N., 1948 (Box 27, Folder 255)
      A Hundred Years of China Methodism
    - "Lessons Learned in China" - papers and correspondence from China Panel, NCCCUSA, 1964-1970 (Box 27, Folder 256)
    - MacInnis, Helen Paulsen, 1950, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 256a)
      "Hong Kong Boat" in World Outlook; "Chinese Women Serve the People" in China Notes
    - Woo, Franklin, 1991-1992, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 257)
      Bartlett Lecture, YDS - "China and New England: Lessons in Self and Society"; "The China Program of the National Council of Churches of Christ in the U.S.A. - Forty Years in Outline"; other reviews, papers
    - Wylie, Ray, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 258)
      China the Peasant Revolution
- Personal Papers, 1948-2004; Series III
  - Correspondence
    - Letters to/from DM while at Fukien Christian University, incl. to Mr. Fair re. use of films in religious education and evangelism, 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 259)
    - Circular and family letters from MacInnises while missionaries in Taiwan, 1955-1964, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 260)
    - Letters from DM to his mother, 1977-1986, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 261)
    - Re. "MacInnis China Fund" held in trusteeship by Wisconsin Methodist Foundation, Inc. (initial funds from estate of DM's mother), 1989-1993 (Box 28, Folder 262)
    - Letter to Erma Martin of North Haven, CT with blueprints of house built by DM, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 263)
    - Letters, journal entries from DM trip to West China and Fujian, incl. re. flood relief, 1998 (Box 28, Folder 264)
    - Letters to children of former Fujian missionaries re. fundraising for flood relief, 1999-2000 (Box 28, Folder 265)
    - Miiscellaneous correspondence from 1990s-2004 (Box 28, Folder 266)
  - Memorabilia and biographical information
    - From period at Fukien Christian University, 1948-1949 (Box 29, Folder 267)
    - From period in Taiwan, incl. re. Methodist Goodwill Services program, 1960-1965, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 268)
    - From 1970s-1980s (Box 29, Folder 269)
    - From 1990s-2005, including CV of DM (Box 29, Folder 270)
- Collected Material, 1928-2004; Series IV
  - Bulletins / Newsletters
    - Amity News Service, 1993-2001 (Box 30, Folder 272-273)
    - Asia Watch, 1993 Jun (Box 30, Folder 274)
    - China Connection, 1989, 2001 Fall no. 60 (Box 30, Folder 275)
    - China News Update, 1992-2000 (Box 30, Folder 276)
    - Foochow News, 1928 Dec 18 vol. III no. 2 (Box 30, Folder 277)
    - International Bulletin of Missionary Research, 1985 Apr. (Box 31, Folder 279)
      Issue on China Mission History guest edited by DM
    - Spotlight on China, 1994 Dec, 1999 Mar, 2004 Mar. (Box 31, Folder 280)
      Quarterly bulletin of the Lutheran Literature Society for the Chinese
    - Tide, 1941, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 281)
      Anglo-Chinese College publication
    - Miscellaneous publications related to Christianity in China (Box 31, Folder 282-283)
  - Re. contemporary China and Taiwan
    - Miscellaneous flyers and notes (Box 31, Folder 284)
    - Papers by Chinese scholars at the Institute for Study of World Religions, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 285)
    - "Learning from Christians in Wuxi" - pamphlet by Theresa Chu, Canada China Programme, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 286)
    - Articles re. family planning, 1989,1992 (Box 32, Folder 287)
    - National Catholic China Conference, U.S. Catholic China Bureau, 1991 Nov (Box 32, Folder 288)
    - "What Future Has Religion in China?" - lecture by Julia Ching, 1992 (Box 32, Folder 289)
    - Re. the Jesus Family sect, 1993-1995, n.d (Box 32, Folder 290)
    - "Fortieth Anniversary of Taichung Methodist Church", 1995 (Box 31, Folder 278)
    - "With Roots and Wing: the Roman Catholic Church in the People's Republic of China Today" - paper by Jean-Paul Wiest, 1996 (Box 32, Folder 291)
    - "Growth Stress: Chinese Protestantism in the 1990s" - paper by Alan Hunter anad Chan Kim-Kwong, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 292)
    - Report of the Carter Center Delegation to Observe Village Elections in China; notes re. Yangkow village, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 293)
    - Miscellaneous articles re. Christianity in China, 1990-1994, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 294)
    - Chinese language articles re. Christianity in China (Box 33, Folder 295-296)
    - "The Methodist Church in the Republic of China Anniversary Yearbook 1953-2003" (Box 33, Folder 297)
  - Poems, songs, prayers, posters
    - "Aids to Prayer" - pamphlet published by Laymen's Missionary Movement, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 298)
    - Posters - Chinese language - re. Christianity, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 299)
    - Chinese hymns, songbooks, poems (Box 34, Folder 300)
    - "Songs of Chinese Children" - translated and arranged by Maryette H. Lum; illustrated by Lin Yu Ts'ang, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 301)
    - "Men's Songs" - Adapted and used by The National Federation of Men's Bible Classes, 1947 (Box 34, Folder 302)
  - Artifacts
    - "The Life of Christ Ten Panels in Wood by Ivan Mestrovic" (Box OV1)
    - Tissue paper with decorative ink (Box OV1)
    - Watanabe prints (Box OV1)
    - Various scrolls (Box OV2)
- Audio-visual Material, 1908-1999; Series V
  - Photographs
    - Canada, Niagara Falls, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 303)
    - China, incl. Inghok, Foochow, Kuliang, Kucheng, Min River, missionaries, Chinese Christians, 1908-1980s (Box 35, Folder 304-305)
    - China, incl. Foochow area, missionaries, Chinese, 1930s-1940s (Box 36, Folder 306)
    - Taichung Methodist Youth Group, 1959 Dec (Box 36, Folder 307)
    - China and Taiwan, 1960s-1990s (Box 37, Folder 308-310)
    - Photocopies of photographs suggested for Min River Journals book (Box 38, Folder 311)
    - Photos of DM and friends; photos from Nicaragua, 1999, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 312)
    - Taiwan Church photos (Box OV1, Folder 3)
    - Miscelleaneous photos from album (Box OV1, Folder 4)
  - Video and audio recordings
    - American Bible Society / The River of Life - The Bible in China" (VHS), 1993; 1 (Box 39, Folder 362, Item barcode 39002098996508)
    - Audio tapes of sermons, lectures, etc. (Box 40)
      Including: "Helen's radio book report and Don's interview with Belinda (Nicaragua); "Lecture/ Sermon delivered by Dr. MacInnis"; "Ron Boccier: The People's Republic of China"; "Lay Spirituality: Joe Holland"; "Memory" by Henri Nouwen"; "Asian Consultation" by Dr. Paul Clasper "Christianity and Asia"; Bishop K. Ting; "Gushan Tape"
    - Audio tapes of sermons, lectures, etc. (Box 41)
      Including: "Golden Slumber"; "Sermons: Elder Ye Zude, Fuzhou Little Flock"; Nanking school; Dr. R.P. Kramers; "Aileen Bridgewater Talk Show"; "Grace in Concert" music; Will Schubert Funeral
    - "The Divinity School Choir Yale University" - LP record (Box OV1)